DAIEI PRESENTS
ROOMS TO LET
Nobody likes this apartment,
because it's too close to the cemetery.
The next room...
How about the next room?
Oh yes, he's a sailor,
but he's not in Japan right now...
And the downstairs rooms?
They're available...
do you want to take a look?
It's all right,
I'll just take this room.
Is that so?
ARU KOROSHIYA
(A CERTAIN KILLER)
Planning: Fujii Haruaki
Based on the novel by
Fujiwara Shinsai
Script: Masumura Yasuzo,
Ishimatsu Aihiro
Cinematographer: Miyagawa Kazuo
Sound recording: Hayashi Tsuchitaro
Lighting: Mima Hiroshi
Art: Oota Seichi
Music: Kaburagi So
Editor: Yaguchi Toshio
Co-director: Ossu Hitoshi
Starring:
Ichikawa Raizo
Nogawa Yumiko
Narita Mikio
Koike Asao
Naghisa Mayumi
Kobayashi Sachiko
Chiba Jutaro
Date Saburo
Matsushita Tatsuo
Directed by
Mori Issei
It's pouring down!
I'm soaking wet!
I'm wondering if this rain
will affect our job...
Maybe it's better like this...
I hope so...
This is so awful...
I'm going to get depressed here.
Take my clothes - for two bowls of
noodle soup, you'll get change, too...
Are you kidding me?
Nobody will give me money for that!
Then what do you want me to do?
Do you think I'm the kind of
woman who eats and runs?
You are taking advantage of me -
I can't let you go...
I see... you think I'm stupid and
are trying to take advantage of me...
- Never! What are you saying?
- I can see it in your face...
Ha! You're making such a fuss
over one bowl of noodle soup.
Go ahead;
do whatever you want to do!
Master, how much do I owe you?
Yes... 380 yen.
I will pay for her soup too...
Mind your own business!
I can't just stand by and watch
a woman sell her body so easily...
This is my business, not yours...
- Is this enough?
- Yes.
Keep the change.
Thank you, sir!
You saved my life.
Hey, why don't you let me
show you my appreciation to you?
Leave me alone!
Wow, you are so cool!
I'm starting to really like you.
Now I'm sure that I have to thank you,
and do something for you in return.
Let's take a rest in there!
Normally I'm not that kind of woman,
but you're such a cool guy,
so don't be shy.
I'm not shy,
but you're annoying me!
You don't have to be embarrassed.
Let's go!
- Keiko!
- Kenji...
What are you doing behind my back?
Ah... this man is forcing me to...
Please help me!
If you've touched my woman...
then I can't let you leave.
Keiko, is this man a mute?
- No, he's not... He can speak.
- Son of a bitch!
I don't know who you are...
but you'd better pay for this.
What do you want me to do?
I could kill you right now, but I'll
let you go if you give me the money.
The money?
Yes, money, but not just a little money.
A large amount of money...
No, I won't...
Do you want me... to kill you?
Wait for me!
You're so strong -
I like strong men.
If you don't take care of his injury,
he's going to be a cripple.
I don't care what happens to him.
You are a cold-hearted woman.
He's your husband, isn't he?
Are you kidding me?
He's just a pimp.
I hope he does become a cripple!
I've always hoped...
that someone like you would
show up and rescue me...
Whatever you say...
But I don't want to get
any more involved with you.
- Welcome back!
- I'm back.
We don't open till 6pm...
"Kikunoya"... is he the owner?
Yes he is...
You're interfering with my work.
What kind of relationship
do you have with him?
'Relationship'?
Yes, relationship...
Are you his lover, or just nothing...
You have no manners!
I'm just a maid.
But you like him, and he has a wife,
so your love is only a one-way street...
No, I don't...
Oh really? That's very good!
Wow, it smells like a man...
You need a woman here.
Why don't you let me work for you?
I'm very good at this kind of job...
That's too bad,
because I don't need help.
Just get out of here!
I have no place to go...
You're just like a balloon, so you can
fly anywhere you want, can't you?
Do you want me to get killed?
If I go back to Kenji...
he'll kill me.
It's not my business whether
or not you get killed.
I'm only 20 years old...
Don't you feel sorry for me?
When I was only 13 years old,
I left home,
and have had a tough life until now.
Men took advantage of me and lied to me,
and took money away from me...
until I can't squeeze tears out
from my eyes anymore,
because I've cried so much...
I'm going to change myself
into a new person and try hard,
so please let me work for you!
You're a dirty old man!
Oh, you're very responsive
for a newcomer!
Yes, I am!
Hey, Midori, bring
another sake over here!
Master, you hit the jackpot,
didn't you?
Eh?
That new girl...
She lights up the place...
Oh yeah?
Oh yes! She looks great, too...
Oh, thank you!
Is she going to keep working here?
I can take care of
this place by myself...
She has no manners and no brains...
I don't even want to look at her face.
I've... been working so hard
for you here...
- I know that.
- Then please let her go!
Anyway, just go home tonight
and we'll see...
How's my service?
I'm so talented, aren't I?
I'm going to give very good service,
and make lots of money for you!
What are you doing?!
Get out of here!
You're so rude!
I don't have any place to go...
- Go look for an apartment!
- But how can I find one so suddenly?
It's not my problem.
I'm not going to let you live here.
Why not?
It's convenient for you, too.
Even if you don't want to,
you must still go...
All right! I will find a room...
Oh, what's so important
this early in the morning?
- I must get ready for opening up.
- Is that so?
I didn't get enough sleep last night,
because he was pestering me all night.
He can't have been...
You never know with a man...
but it all depends on who he's with...
From now on,
I don't know what I'm going
to do with him every night!
It's unbelievable...
Anyway, from now on,
I'm the boss here,
so you'd better listen to me...
No, I won't.
I can't work for you!
Oh yeah? Are you going to quit?
Of course I am!
How can I keep working here...
after the Master betrayed me?
I quit!
What happened to Midori?
Good morning!
My body aches all over...
I slept here last night, because
I didn't have any other place to go.
What were you talking about with her?
- She said she's going to quit today.
- Quit?!
She must be shocked,
what with me showing up so suddenly.
You chased her out, didn't you?
Why should I do that?
It doesn't matter to me
whether she's here or not...
Well, we'll have to try harder, because
I'm going to be on my own from now on...
I'm going to the beauty parlour.
It's nice out now...
The rain has stopped.
Please go get some food for tonight.
Why don't we go out to eat?
It's not a good idea
to show up in public.
My clothes are still wet,
so is it OK if I get changed first?
No, I can't wait. Please go now!
I'm going to catch a cold...
Come rain or wind,
I don't change my plans.
That is my policy.
I understand.
You act like a husband
all of a sudden.
If you don't like it,
you can leave right now.
Don't be reserved!
I'm listening, I'm listening!
Master, please make up
three packs of sushi, to go!
- Thanks for waiting.
- Thank you.
Are you Shiozawa?
Excuse me - my name is Maeda,
of the Kimura family.
What do you want?
To tell you the truth...
some of our members...
were tricked by another family
in a business deal.
Do you know a man named Oowada?
Yes, I've heard the name...
That son of a bitch -
he's also a yakuza,
yet he took away all of our business,
betraying the code of the yakuza.
We kept our eyes open,
looking for the chance to get him,
but he's so cautious,
he doesn't let us get close to him.
My boss thinks that the only person
who can get to him is you...
So, how about it?
I can't accept your request.
We know that you don't normally
accept this kind of job,
but please think about it carefully.
This is a matter of life or death
for the Kimura family.
It's none of my concern if a yakuza
family is destroyed or survives...
Please don't be so cold-hearted.
My boss said if you'll accept
our request...
he'll pay you five million yen.
Please don't get upset,
but accept his offer... please!
The answer's no.
Won't you change your mind?
As I thought...
he wouldn't accept it.
I'm sorry, but no matter
how we approach it,
he's not going to accept,
because he's no ordinary hitman.
I've heard that
he's not an easy man...
but can we somehow
talk him into this?
I don't think so...
It's not necessary
to pay him five million yen.
You still can't judge who is who...
I'm Kimura.
Sorry about the young member
who I sent to meet you the other day.
I'm sure that you know
about Oowada now.
The Oowada family
is the group that operates...
the prostitution
and extortion rackets...
but the Kimura family
are honest yakuza,
who work hard in
the construction business.
But Oowada uses
his money and power to...
take away all our business from us...
the dishonest people grow fat
on his wallet,
and the honest ones get poor...
This can't be right.
"The honest ones"?
That's you, is it?
Heh, heh, heh...
I'm just comparing us against Oowada.
We can't get him without your help,
so please...
just take look at this picture...
The man standing
in the middle is Oowada...
and, as you can see,
he has his body guards
around him always.
They're all professionals
in the underground,
so my youngster couldn't even
get near them.
You're the only one who can break
through that circle of men.
If you won't help me,
I must give up...
So, please save my life!
All my friends died with trust
in their country...
and for the good of the nation...
They were all pure and young...
They're not worthy of this world,
they're just like cockroaches.
So you're going to help us?
Oh, that's good... if you help me,
Oowada is as good as dead.
But I want 20 million yen.
20 million yen?!
Boss, if Oowada dies,
how much can you make,
with all the extra work you'll get?
If you say it's too much money,
I won't do it.
Just a minute! I am willing
to pay you 20 million yen...
in exchange,
you'd better move fast!
You just let me decide when.
I know that you take your time with
this kind of job, but I'm in a hurry...
If you know how I work,
please don't give me orders.
If you do, I won't to do the job...
OK, OK!
I won't say anything more.
My respects.
- How was it?
- As you'd expect.
As I thought... He said no...
Don't be an idiot!
I'm not like you!
Welcome!
She's not a familiar face,
but she's good-looking...
Welcome!
- Does she come here often?
- Yes, lately, every once in a while.
- Hmmm... is she always alone?
- Yes.
Is that so...
- Oh!
- Right on time.
Shiozawa is very strict.
As tonight is going to be his last night,
let him do whatever he wants to.
Take a look at that.
This is a garbage dump, isn't it?
No, this is Shiozawa's grave...
If we put his body down there,
nobody will ever find him.
I see...
Nobody will come here...
- Where is his apartment?
- It's over there.
- How about Shiozawa?
- He's inside.
I told you to come separately.
By chance, we met outside...
By the way,
this is an awful room!
I know. He didn't have
to rent such an awful room;
he could have got a nice hotel room,
or something...
Don't you tell me what to do!
If someone comes...
we can go over the roof
to that warehouse to escape.
I see...
as we thought,
you really are thorough.
You don't have to try to make me feel good,
but try to remember our plan...
so you don't make any mistakes.
- What's wrong?
- It's the police!
- He's coming this way.
- Maybe he's looking for you...
Don't worry:
we haven't done anything wrong yet...
Then... why he is here?
- I'm going to go check.
- Don't do that!
If he sees your face,
it's going to be complicated later.
If he takes his time, it will affect
our job tonight, won't it?
Just relax!
Just stay still in here.
Old lady... old lady!
Do you still just have
that sailor living here?
Eh?
- Is there just a sailor living here?
- Oh, no...
Did anybody rent this place?
Yes, only one more...
But he's a nice man.
He doesn't mind being so close
to the cemetery.
Do you know his name and occupation?
It's okay now...
Ouch!
What's wrong?
Thanks for coming!
Please, this way...
- Who's that young girl?
- She's Mr. Oowada's wife.
Heh... She looks more
like his daughter...
- He's so lucky!
- Yes, he is...
Where is the backstage room?
Oh, yes - you're in the show?
I'll show you the way.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- It's just in there.
- Thanks. - OK.
- Good morning!
This is our construction
company's 30th year,
and we are hoping
that we will continue to...
expand our business
with your support, and...
if you provide us
with more business,
we will try our best
for future success...
Thank you very much!
Boss!
Finally, he did it!
Just as we thought, he's great!
The police are investigating
about this.
I guess they will come here
to question us...
We have an alibi, right?
So there's nothing to be afraid of.
Well...
As I promised, I'm going to pay him
his 20 million yen.
It's a very good business, isn't it?
Now, I'm going to take Oowada's
businesses, too...
It's all there.
I'm so impressed
by how good you are...
Especially this time,
your techniques were unbelievable!
Please stop it!
Hah, hah, hah... Sorry!
By the way,
I want to ask you a favour.
What is it?
Please take me on, as your pupil.
- A pupil?
- Yes...
After I saw your work,
I finally realized what
I really want to do.
I want to learn from you,
and become a real man, just like you.
You're mistaken! Do you really
think what I do is a real man's job?
Then why are you doing it?
I have a good reason to do it,
but it's none of your business.
Please don't say that -
I'm sure there'll be something
I can do to help you in the future...
so, please think about it.
I don't trust anybody, and so
I must do my job alone. Also...
I prefer to go to the place of
execution alone... If I have to...
That's what I like about you...
I don't want you to copy me.
Please don't come back here again!
I see...
but I am not going to give up.
I will be back again.
Oh! Didn't I see you the other day?
Are you a friend of Shiozawa's?
Yes, I live here.
- Are you his wife?
- Yes, I am.
Oh? Well... excuse me!
Who was that?
Nobody...
Sorry about the other day...
but, can I join you?
Oh, please do. It doesn't matter,
because I'm alone anyway...
Excuse me, my name is Maeda.
My name is Keiko.
Very pleased to meet you.
Welcome!
- Please give me the same as her.
- OK, Sir.
I must admit, I'm jealous of
Mr. Shiozawa,
having such a beautiful wife as you...
Oh, you talk very nicely...
Anyway, if a man has
lots of money like him,
he can get any girl he wants.
How much money can a man who
just owns a small business have?
Come now, that business
is just a side-business.
He has some other large income
from other business, doesn't he?
You're a lucky lady...
Maybe so...
By the way, did you come over just
to talk about the other day?
Er, yes... what else?
Good morning!
You're early, aren't you?
Am I? I want to talk to you.
What is it?
It's been months since I came here,
and I'm sure that you know by now...
what kind of a woman I am,
don't you?
- Hey, please listen to me!
- I am listening.
I want to be your wife...
- I don't need a wife.
- Why is that?
You're not impotent, are you?
I don't want to talk about it!
Even if you don't,
I still want to be your wife.
Then, you must quit working here.
Then go ahead and fire me!
But, if you do,
I'll tell about your other job...
My 'other job'...?
Your other job is a hitman, isn't it?
Who told you that?
I'm not telling you.
If you want to kill me,
then go ahead and kill me.
I know I'm risking my life,
saying this.
Let me be your wife!
No, I won't!
Don't you care
what will happen to you?
I'll tell the police about your work.
Be my guest! I have nothing
to fear from the police.
- I'd like some tea...
- I'll go downstairs and get it.
It's not a good idea
if someone sees you...
But we're so thirsty!
You're not going
to die without water.
We can sleep for about 7 hours,
until 3 o'clock.
Are we going to sleep already?
If we don't get enough sleep,
then we can't do our job well.
So, you'd better get some rest!
I can't sleep this early...
Until the time comes,
it's best to forget about the job.
It's not a good idea
to put garbage together.
- Why is that?
- If they find three empty boxes,
they will know that
there were three of us.
It's best to take our garbage with us
when we leave, and then throw it away.
You're so cautious...
If you're lazy,
you can't do a perfect job.
I understand.
- What are you doing?!
- I just want to touch you.
I'm somebody's wife, you know?!
I'll tell Shiozawa about you...
Enough is enough!
Being like that when
I'm just trying to be nice to you,
and when I know you're just
his maid, and not his wife.
You knew?
Shiozawa's wife wouldn't live
in a place like this.
You're so smart, aren't you?
Why don't you quit the Kikunoya
and become my wife?
Do you like me that much?
You do, too, don't you?
- Yes, but I don't want to live with you.
- Why's that?
You don't have feelings
for Shiozawa, do you?
Yes, I do.
- What do you see in him?
- He's richer than you are,
because he got 20 million yen
the other day.
It would be very foolish
to leave him right now.
You care more for money
than for romance!
If I could have both,
it would be nice...
Don't you think so?
You're thinking of doing something
to Shiozawa, aren't you?
You're right! If we got together,
we could get rid of him...
Do you want to do it?
I was hoping you'd say that...
I knew you were my kind of a guy,
but I never thought that
we could agree so easily.
But he's a very tough one -
we won't get rid of him so easily...
Thanks for last time I saw you...
Didn't I tell you not to come
around here anymore?
Yes, you did, but I brought
some good news today...
I'm talking about 200 million yen...
Will you just listen to me?
What's this all about?
Did you know that Oowada
was dealing in drugs?
Yeah.
After Oowada passed away,
his group was broken up into pieces,
and now nobody can keep
their eyes on each other,
so I want to get my hands
on their drugs,
which they are buying
in large quantities.
I got this information
from a very reliable source.
The boat that Oowada owned
carries the drugs.
It will enter the Bay area
three days from now.
A top member named Joe
will bring the boat in,
and meet two other guys
in the Bay area.
So, if we can get
those three guys,
all the drugs, worth about
200 million yen, will be ours.
Why don't you tell
Mr. Kimura about this?
If he gets involved in this plan,
I'll end up with nothing!
Anyway, like I told you before...
I want you to teach me
how to handle a job like this.
I took a chance and decided
to ask you, instead of my boss...
so please say yes!
Are you sure about this?
Of course I'm sure,
because I checked up on everything
I heard myself.
There are three guys...
Yes, there are... but with your skills,
it'll be an easy job.
Let's do it!
Thank you!
I want to talk to you.
Come inside!
What do you want to talk to me about?
We will get 50 million yen each...
do you want to do it?
Of course I do!
Are you going to let a woman
get involved in this?
I'll decide what to do
about this job.
Of course you will...
Listen! This job is all about timing.
If the timing is right,
the job will be as well,
but if the timing is out,
we'll get caught...
So, you must tighten up
your belts and do the job.
Yes... we will...
What about preparations...
Firstly, we're going to rent
a room in the Bay area.
Rent a room?
If we are walking around the scene
of the job, then people will see us,
but if we have a room nearby,
we can hide if the situation
becomes dangerous...
I'm going to find a room,
so you come to the place separately,
and make sure that nobody sees you.
I understand.
Get up!
Is it time already?
You know what to do, don't you?
I just keep on Joe's tracks
when he leaves, don't I?
Right...
because if he leaves a little early,
our plan is going to be out of order...
So, let's get to the hut
a little bit early!
Okay, sir!
This is just in case.
If you want to use this, you must
prepare yourself to go to jail.
If you don't want to go to the place
of execution, don't use it!
Maeda is late...
I wonder if he's all right.
Maybe he got scared
and changed his mind...
He's a greedy man,
so he'll be here soon.
I wonder if this is all for real...
maybe he told us a story...
He doesn't have the nerve
to betray a man like me.
Hey, just calm down!
He's here!
You're late!
I don't know why,
but they were taking their time...
How about Joe?
Delayed 30 minutes;
he took the boat to get the drugs.
Are you sure that his boat will come
back to the landfill site?
Yes, it will, and the two others
will be coming over here very soon.
I don't have a good feeling
about this...
My goodness gracious!
- Leave them alone!
- Let's tease them!
They're going to be surprised
and run away...
It's all right, please keep going!
What's the matter, Mark?
Are you ready?
If you send the wrong signal,
I'll kill you.
Tie him up!
- Are you okay?
- About what?
Can you kill him?
Just watch me!
Are you alone?
Yeah... where are the drugs?
The drugs?
Who are you?
Can't you tell me?
Huh?
Yes, this is good quality...
How much is it worth altogether?
- About 200 million yen.
- What?!
Even if we sell it on the street,
we can get at least 150 million.
Do you believe me now?
By the way, Maeda...
do you want it as it is,
or will you wait to get cash?
You needn't worry about that!
Your job is over,
and now you must get lost...
I took this from your money safe -
please don't hate me!
You'd better stop being so stupid!
Honey, what are you doing?
Go ahead and kill him!
You are too naive...
you can't see the future.
Put away that gun.
Shoot him now! Kill him!
What's wrong with you?
Hurry, kill him!
Don't be a big shot!
If you don't want to die, you'd better
go down on your knees and beg me...
- so I can laugh at you.
- You're being a hard head!
You thought you were on the
same level as me, didn't you?
But you made a big mistake...
I knew this was going
to end like this,
so I removed the bullets
ahead of time...
I've thought the same way as you,
every time I took a job with someone.
But I never betrayed anyone.
You won!
Go ahead and do whatever
you want to do!
What are you doing?
The job is the job...
Just take it!
Shiozawa...
They're after us! Get ready!
You are Oowada's men?
Huh? Boss!
It's a very bad situation for you,
because you did a big job behind my back...
- I didn't mean to do it...
- You don't need an excuse!
I kept an eye on you,
because I knew you were sneaky.
Shiozawa, thanks for your hard work,
but I will take the drugs now.
I'm not so stupid as to take drugs
from one rogue...
and then give them to another.
Don't be a wise guy!
I told the police that you're a hitman,
so now they'll come after you.
You can't escape now...
Please give me that!
And it would be nice for us
if the three of you die here now,
especially since you already...
set the place up for it...!
Don't come any closer!
I'll shoot!
You... Maeda!
Empty guns are very useful
sometimes, aren't they?
I'm sorry, Shiozawa!
Please forgive me!
Please, I beg you!
I never did any jobs
before that weren't for money,
but you're a special case...
Please don't kill me!
Shiozawa, wait!
Please take me with you!
I don't like a man who
doesn't know the difference...
between the job and the romance!
Share it between the two of you.
Oh, that was too much!
But I'm so glad,
because we're still alive.
Where are you going?
It's none of your business!
Why are you saying that now?
Please take me with you!
Women don't know the difference
between the job and the romance...
sorry.
I don't need you, anyway...
I'm going to find a better partner
and make lots of money...
THE END
Subtitles by Lord Retsudo